♪Minimal Ivan♪
♪最小伊文♪
♪Your roots hold tight♪
♪你的根紧紧抓住♪
♪In this land♪
♪在这片土地上♪
♪Mengejar Mbake♪
♪门格贾尔·姆巴克♪
♪My leaves are flying♪
♪我的树叶飞过♪
♪ A border of thousands of stones ♪
♪数千块石头的边界♪
♪Looking at each other from a distance♪
♪远远地看着对方♪
♪The edge of the cliff is♪
♪悬崖的边缘是♪
♪Together forever♪
♪永远在一起♪
♪When we meet again and separate♪
♪当我们再次相遇又分开时♪
♪When we depend on each other and are apart♪
♪当我们相依为命 而疏远时♪
♪I will never forget♪
♪我永远不会忘记♪
♪The light reflected on the sword and knife♪
♪剑和刀上反射的光♪
♪Light up the dark sky♪
♪照亮昏暗的天空♪
♪Abandoned dream♪
♪被遗弃的梦想♪
♪Blowed to pieces by the wind♪
♪被风吹碎♪
♪Go against the direction of the wind and waves♪
♪逆着风浪的方向♪
♪See thousands of ships crossing♪
♪看到成千上万的船只穿越♪
♪The world has changed♪
♪这个世界改变了♪
♪Makeup and armor swaying in the wind♪
♪妆容随风 摇曳的铠甲♪
♪Drinking ice, the blood cannot cool down, and dreaming about the joy of love♪
♪喝冰，血难凉， 梦想着恋爱的乐趣♪
♪I just hope you are by my side♪
♪只希望 你在我身边♪
♪Don’t waste your spring time♪
♪别浪费春天的时光♪
♪Trees reach the sky, their roots are connected, friends uphold justice in the world♪
♪树参天，根相连， 朋友主持天下正义♪
♪See the sparkle on your shoulders♪
♪看到肩膀上闪烁的光芒♪
♪There are no regrets in this world♪
♪这世上没有遗憾♪
=Wonderland of Love=
=爱的仙境=
(Laolan border) ♪The Laolan River has eighteen bays♪
（老兰边境） ♪老兰河有十八湾♪
♪The first bay is Silver Pine Ridge♪
♪第一湾是银松岭♪
♪Silver Pine Ridge♪
♪银松岭♪
Change controller group!
更改控制器组！
♪Ikan bilis♪
♪江鱼仔♪
Bro, let’s eat cake!
兄弟，我们吃蛋糕吧！
(Instructor Bao of the Zhenxi Army) Drink water first.
（镇西军教官鲍） 先喝水。
Add more water.
添加更多的水。
Don't fight.
别打架。
Everyone is there.
每个人都在那里。
Everyone can get it.
每个人都可以得到它。
How does it feel?
感觉如何？
- delicious!
- 可口的！
precious,
宝，
You imitate the way I make cookies,
你模仿我做饼干的方式，
But won't you leave me a copy?
但不给我留一份吗？
Eat
吃吧，
(Zhenxi Army Commander Li Ni) Why are you talking so much?
（镇西军长李妮） 你说这么多干嘛？
No.
不。
you,
你，
Don't try to cover my mouth with cookies.
别试图 用饼干捂住我的嘴。
In the kitchen,
在厨房，
You are still noisy
你还是吵闹
and say a bag
并说一个袋子
High quality wheat flour.
优质小麦粉。
this is what everyone else does
这就是其他人所做的
Send from a distance
从远处发送
Make the 17th cucunda snack.
制作第 17 个 cucunda 小吃。
Do you still dare to steal this?
你还敢偷这个吗？
Don't talk nonsense.
别胡言乱语。
no one in the kitchen
厨房里没有人
So I took some.
所以我拿了一些。
steal a bag
偷一个包
Or a little bit the same.
或者有一点相同。
Theft of military rations is a serious crime.
盗窃军粮 是严重犯罪行为。
Do you realize your mistake?
你意识到 自己的错误了吗？
I take something
我拿东西
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
Shi Qi once said
石奇曾经说过
There is no need to distinguish between Royal Kukunda and the public.
没有必要区分皇家库昆达 和公众。
everyone will share
大家都会分享
Happy and sad together!
快乐和悲伤在一起！
He will eat whatever we eat !
我们吃什么他都会 吃！
correct?
正确的？
-ah!
-呀！
Yes.
是的。
There is an enemy!
有敌人了！
quickly!
快速地！
(Penyuluh Tentera Zhenxi, Xie Chang'er)
(Penyuluh Tentera Zhenxi, Xie Chang'er)
arrow.
箭。
get ready.
准备好。
We are the Zhenxi Guards.
我们是镇西保卫军。
Ini Panglima Pei Xian.
Ini Panglima Pei Xian.
We are not an army of punishment;
我们不是一支受惩罚的军队，
We are not your enemies!
我们不是你的敌人！
We are the Zhenxi Defense Force.
我们是镇西国防军。
(Zhenxi)
(Zhenxi)
Greetings, Prince.
问候，王子。
Park Ci-bae.
朴慈培.
Three days ago, Wanxi received an emergency report from Balelaya, Hejian.
三天前，皖西接到 来自河间巴莱拉亚的紧急报告。
His Majesty
陛下
(Paglima Besar Zhenxi, Pei Xian) dianiaya oleh Sun Jing yang keji
(Panglima Besar Zhenxi, Pei Xian) dianiaya oleh Sun Jing yang keji
At a birthday party on the sixth day of June.
在六月初六的生日聚会上。
He has passed away.
他已经去世了。
The villain incited Wang Jun
恶人 煽动王军
Close the castle and kill everyone in the capital.
关闭城堡 并杀死首都的所有人。
The prince died for his country.
太子为国捐躯。
The king, princes and grandsons were also killed.
国王、王子和孙子 也被杀。
Many princesses and concubines were also killed or injured.
许多公主和妃嫔 也死伤了。
Yun Changshuai Han Chang protected his great-grandson.
云长帅韩昌 保护了他的曾孙。
He kills anyone who gets in his way
他杀死一切阻碍他的人
And leave the capital.
并出首都。
They were separated by rebels outside the capital
他们在京城外被叛军分开
Life and death are no longer certain.
生与死不再确定。
Where is my father?
我父亲呢？
King Liang did not enter the palace due to illness
梁王因病未入宫
Then escape this disaster.
然后逃离 这场灾难。
Now, King Liang is being held hostage.
现在，梁王被扣为 人质。
prince,
王子，
The king was killed.
国王被杀了。
Now only King Liang is left.
现在只剩下梁王了。
Patik has made a decision with Balai Raja Jenxi .
Patik已经和Balai Raja Jenxi做出了决定 。
We support King Liang as emperor
我们拥立梁王 为帝
And worship the prince as the prince
并拜太子 为太子
Gather an army to help the Emperor.
集结军队 帮助皇帝。
Please accept our request.
请接受我们的请求。
Panglima Pei,
Panglima Pei,
I cannot agree to your request.
我不能同意 你的要求。
Mr. Prince.
普林斯先生。
——Prince Adult!
——王子大人！
The status of his great-grandson is unclear;
他的曾孙的地位尚不清楚，
Maybe he's still alive.
也许他还活着。
The emperor died , and so did the prince.
皇帝死了 ，太子也死了。
His great-grandson should be supported to inherit the throne.
应该支持他的曾 孙继承王位。
Although his great-grandson is still alive,
虽然他的曾孙还活着，
he's just a boy
他只是个男孩
Who is seven or eight years old.
谁七八岁了。
He is only the eldest son of the Crown Prince.
他只是皇太子的长子。
Nor was he given a title.
他也没有被授予头衔。
There are wars going on all over the country now.
现在全国各地都在发生战争。
Our country has arrived
我们的国家已经到来
Time determines the life or death of an empire .
时间决定一个帝国的生死 。
how can we
我们怎样才能
let immature boys
让不成熟的男孩
What about our emperor?
那么我们的皇帝呢？
Panglima Pei.
Panglima Pei.
His great-grandson is very smart.
他的曾孙非常聪明。
He is also the eldest son,
他也是长子，
He has the right to inherit the throne.
他有权继承王位。
Actually,
实际上，
My father was captured by Sun Jing.
我的父亲被孙敬俘虏了。
If you want me to be governor
如果你要我当州长
Will this be inconvenient?
这会不会不方便
my father?
我的父亲？
prince!
王子！
——Prince Adult!
——王子大人！
(Zhenxi) (Cucunda ke-17, Li Ni)
(Zhenxi) (Cucunda ke-17, Li Ni)
(memimpin Tentera Zhenxi)
(memimpin Tentera Zhenxi)
(Starting from Laolan border and heading south)
（从老兰边境出发 向南）
(Go to the capital, Xichang, to eliminate the rebels.)
（前往首都西昌 消灭叛乱分子。）
(They want to save King Liang)
（他们是想 救梁王）
(And revived the Yu Empire.)
（并复兴了大禹帝国。）
(at the same time,)
（同时，）
(Paglima Besar Pingliang, Cui Yi)
(Panglima Besar Pingliang, Cui Yi)
(Pointing to his only child Cui Lin)
（指着他唯一的孩子崔琳）
(Leading Cui Jiajun to set off from Yingzhou)
（率领崔家军 从瀛州出发）
(And attack Xiba Jing.)
（并攻打西场京。）
(They wanted to kill Sun Jing and usurp the throne.)
（他们想杀孙敬 篡位。）
(Two armies clash,)
（两军交锋，）
(Who can win)
（谁能赢）
(Calm down the whole world?)
（让整个世界平静下来？）
=Episode 1=
=第1集=
(Dewan Zhilu)
(Dewan Zhilu)
(Yue, a musician from Zhilutang Hall)
（智禄堂音乐演奏家岳）
Your father can no longer take pictures of you.
你父亲不能再给你拍照了。
Is it possible?
是否可以？
(Panglima Zhenxi, Pei Yuan)
(Panglima Zhenxi, Pei Yuan)
You are indeed the greatest counselor.
你确实是最伟大的辅导员
The entire former Laolan border,
整个以前的老兰边境，
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
Indeed this is your attitude,
确实这就是你的态度，
You have to catch Pease too.
你也必须来抓皮斯。
Pei Yuan, I am so excited to be the commander-in-chief.
裴渊，当上总司令真是太兴奋了。
I'm here to arrest someone
我是来抓人的
But your dad is acting like I'm going to be arrested
但你父亲的表现就像 我要被逮捕一样
by others.
由其他人。
now you
现在轮到你
Commander-in-Chief of the Armed Forces.
武装部队总司令。
Isn't my father just worried that you are in danger?
我父亲不是只是担心 你有危险吗？
of.
的。
I want to attack the capital
我要进攻 到首都
Killed the deserter Sun Jing,
杀了 逃兵孙靖，
Save your father and welcome his great-grandson back,
救救你的父亲 ，迎接他的曾孙归来，
and the establishment of the Empire of Yu.
以及建立大禹帝国。
OK
好的。
Then?
然后？
Then of course I will come back
那么我当然会回来
And live freely on the border of Laolan.
并在老兰边境自由自在地生活。
When there is no war,
没有战争的时候，
Isn’t it fun to hunt goats?
狩猎山羊不是很有趣吗？
I knew it
我就知道
You have to go back to the Laolan border.
你要回老兰边境。
How fun is Laolan Border?
老兰边境有多好玩？
Doesn’t the roasted goat there taste delicious?
包那里烤的山羊 味道不香吗？
are you hungry?
你饿了吗？
After thinking about it?
想了想之后呢？
hungry.
饥饿的。
I'm really hungry.
我真的很饿。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
our armed forces
我们的武装部队
Starved.
挨饿了。
our wounded soldiers
我们的受伤士兵
You can only eat twice a day.
一天只能吃两次。
if we
要是我们
Still no food supply,
仍然没有食物供应，
Not to mention attacking Xichang Jing,
别说攻打西昌泾，
our armed forces
我们的武装部队
Will starve to death.
会饿死的。
So, no matter what,
所以，无论怎样，
Today we must seize
今天我们必须抓住
Pi Si
Pi Si
Seizure of supplies
扣押物资
He sent someone to find Sun Jing.
他派人去找孙敬。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Everything is ready.
一切都准备好了。
We just have to wait for Pease to fall into the trap.
我们只需要等待 皮斯落入陷阱即可。
(Cui Jiajun bodyguard Shu)
（崔家军侍卫舒）
(Cui Jiajun, Lieutenant He)
（崔家军、何中尉）
Let's leave.
咱们离开吧。
Yue, here I come.
悦，我来了。
Pease came out.
皮斯出来了。
I'm going to go in and catch him.
我要进去抓他。
Go back and tell Pei Yuan
你回去告诉裴媛
so that they could cause a commotion in the hall first
以便他们先在大厅里引起骚动
To delay time.
以拖延时间。
-OK!
-好的！
Cik Yue,
Cik Yue,
You're great at playing the pipes.
你吹管子很厉害。
Let go.
放手。
Can a rude person like you hold Miss Yue's hand?
你这种粗鲁的人能 握住岳小姐的手吗？
Let go!
放手！
You are rude!
你粗鲁！
I bought Miss Yue a glass of wine. What does that have to do with you?
我给岳小姐请了一杯酒， 跟你有什么关系？
customer,
顾客，
Cik Yue just played this song.
Cik Yue刚刚播放了这首歌。
I'll throw walnuts at you!
我往你身上扔核桃！
No...
不...
Customers.
顾客们。
what happened?
发生了什么？
Don't do that.
不要那样做。
do not fight.
不要打架。
miss.
错过。
Why hasn't Yue come back yet?
岳怎么还没回来？
This song only plays in heaven,
这首歌只在天堂奏响，
(Mishang Pease)
（米商皮斯）
There are few opportunities to listen in this world.
在人间很少有机会聆听。
Joy,
悦，
Not in vain
没有白费
I came here specially
我特意来到这里
Listen to your pipes.
聆听你的管乐。
I want to give this to Yue.
我想把这个送给岳。
He won't like this old-fashioned stuff.
他不会喜欢这种老式的东西。
This is also true.
这也是对的。
Joy,
悦，
You will love this.
你一定会喜欢这个。
Joy.
悦。
Is Yue here?
岳在吗？
Yue, I have been waiting for you for a long time.
悦，我等你很久了。
Miss, don't be angry anymore.
小姐，别再生气了。
Yue, what happened?
悦，发生什么事了？
what happened?
发生了什么？
(Dewan Zhilu)
(Dewan Zhilu)
customer.
顾客。
Customers, don't leave yet.
顾客们，先别走。
This...all customers
这...所有顾客
Listening to music in the front room.
正在前厅听歌。
If you need anything,
如果你需要什么东西，
you can continue
你可以继续
(Sun Jing's subordinate Yu San) inform me.
（孙敬部下于三） 通知我。
(Sun Jing’s subordinate Yu San)
皮斯呢？
Skin...
皮...
You are also a customer here,
您也是这里的顾客，
But you want to ask about other people.
但你想询问其他人的情况。
this...
这...
Sorry because I can't tell you.
抱歉，因为我不能告诉你。
We are the subordinates of Commander Guo Zhi.
我们是郭志司令的部下。
if you get in the way of our mission
如果你妨碍我们的任务
Can you bear this sin?
你能 承受这个罪孽吗？
where is the music player
音乐播放器在哪里
The one named Yue?
那个叫岳的？
This is it
就是这个
A gift I prepared just for you.
我专门为你准备的礼物。
Beautiful jade matches a beautiful girl.
美丽的玉石配上 美丽的姑娘。
How do you like it?
你喜欢吗？
Joy,
悦，
Actually a long time ago
其实很久以前
I'm waiting for today
我在等今天
because i want you
因为我要你
Play a song for me.
为我播放一首歌吧。
How do you work?
你如何工作的？
You let customers in without permission.
你未经允许就让顾客进来。
Aren't you afraid that Qiutaoke will break your legs?
你不怕秋涛克 打断你的腿吗？
No, it has nothing to do with them.
不，这与他们无关。
I sneaked in.
我偷偷溜了进去。
Joy,
悦，
Stop being angry, okay?
别再生气了，好吗？
I will give you another gift next time.
下次我会再送 你一份礼物。
Is it possible?
是否可以？
Drink more water.
多喝水。
Joy!
悦！
I didn't expect you to be hiding someone in the room!
没想到你竟然 在房间里藏人了！
Are you hiding two people?
你藏着两个人吗？
Don't get me wrong.
不要误解。
We have no choice but to be included here.
我们别无选择，只能 被包括在这里。
please forgive us.
请原谅我们。
You are indeed shameless!
确实你无耻！
Get out of my room!
滚出我的房间！
OK
好的。
-I know you're not like this. - Change the water in the pool. Get him out.
-我知道你不是这样的。 - 更换泳池中的水。把他赶出去。
-All right.
-好吧。
I was the one who got it wrong.
我就是那个误会的人。
-Wake up quickly. - Joy.
-快速醒来。 - 悦。
-Don't pull me, Yue. ——Wake up, come out quickly.
-别拉我，岳。 ——醒醒，快点出来。
Don't drive me away!
别赶我走！
-Pi Si! -Yue!
-Pi Si! -Yue!
go out.
出去。
How dare you sneak out of the accommodation center
你怎么敢偷偷溜出 住宿中心
come here?
来这里？
Bring him back!
把他带回来！
OK!
好的！
Do you know my identity?
你知道我的身份吗？
Let me go!
让我走！
Let go!
放手！
Who are you?
你是谁？
This is a lonely page,
这是一个孤独的页面，
You woman, why are you here?
你这个女人，你为什么来这里？
Who said I'm a woman?
谁说我是女人？
The feet are smooth.
足部光滑。
Slim waist.
纤细的腰身。
The shoulders are not strong.
肩膀不坚固。
You also said you are not a woman?
你还说你不是女人？
Lieutenant.
中尉。
hurry up.
快点。
And you?
你呢？
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Are you hurt
你受伤了吗
so.
所以。
who is he?
他是谁？
He fought four guys , but it was still a game.
他与四个人打架 ，但仍然是一场比赛。
Maybe he is Sun Jing's army?
也许他是孙靖的军队？
so,
所以，
Even if he uses a knife,
即使他用刀，
He uses swordsmanship.
他使用剑术。
On the contrary, the sword is swung smoothly
反而剑挥得很流畅
Like a storm.
像一场暴风雨。
It's the same as technology
这和技术是一样的
There is no inheritance for Commander Pei to anyone.
没有继承 给任何人的裴司令。
others say
别人说
Panglima Pei
Panglima Pei
Once taught the prince.
曾经教过王子。
No...
不...
The Li family is old and lazy.
李家老了，又懒。
I've never even heard of it
我什至从未听说过
Lee family
李氏家族
There are useful people.
有有用的人。
They can't be good at swordsmanship either.
他们不可能 也擅长剑术。
most likely
最有可能的
This person is the son or disciple of the Pei family.
此人是裴家的儿子或者弟子。
who is he?
他是谁？
Very difficult to deal with.
很难处理。
Maybe he is the bodyguard sent by Sun Jing?
或许他就是孙静派来的保镖？
No, he is not Sun Jing's bodyguard,
不，他不是孙静的保镖，
He is not Guo Zhi's army either.
他也不是郭治的军队。
He is a member of the Cui family army and the Cui family.
他是崔家军的人， 是崔家的人。
Cui Jiajun?
崔家军？
The Cui family has been guarding Pingliang.
崔家一直 在平凉镇守。
How come they are here?
他们怎么会出现在这里？
Sun Jing rebelled and killed the emperor.
孙敬叛乱 ，杀了皇帝。
Cui left Yingzhou
崔氏离开瀛州
On the grounds of saving the country.
以救国为由。
The world is in chaos now,
现在世界一片混乱，
Of course they had other plans.
当然他们还有其他计划。
Since a few months ago,
从几个月前开始，
Cui used the excuse of saving the country
崔氏 以救国为借口
attract many cities.
吸引许多城市。
Selain Tentera Zhenxi
Selain Tentera Zhenxi
And Sun Jing’s army,
还有孙敬的军队，
Cui Jiajun only
仅限崔家军
The most powerful.
最厉害的。
I didn't expect the Cui family to move so quickly.
没想到崔家 行动得这么快。
The speed at which they entered Wangzhou City.
他们进入望州城的速度。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
they are just like us
他们就像我们一样
Who sneaks into the city.
谁偷偷潜入城市。
What should I say, take this opportunity...
怎么说呢，趁这个机会...
so.
所以。
The Cui family makes excuses
崔家找借口
Ordered to save the country.
奉命救国。
As they set out to save the country,
当他们 开始拯救国家时，
we must tolerate
我们必须容忍
Look how they saved the country.
看看他们如何 拯救国家。
Lieutenant, please eat.
中尉，请吃饭。
It's a pity that we couldn't catch the food seller today.
可惜今天没能 抓住那个食品贩子，
Pi Si.
Pi Si.
Indeed, the lieutenant's ability to predict was great.
确实，中尉的预测能力很强。
The lieutenant knew that the Zhenxi Army was short of food and grass.
中尉知道镇西军 粮草不足
They'll probably target Pease.
他们很可能 会针对皮斯。
Unexpectedly, it was the Pei family of the Zhenxi Army.
没想到 是镇西军的裴家
Coming soon.
很快就会来。
Panglima Tentera Zhenxi, Pei Xian
Panglima Tentera Zhenxi, Pei Xian
Ask Kukunda Lini
询问库昆达·李妮
serve as commander in chief
担任总司令
Gather the troops to save the country.
集结军队 救国。
I think Pei Xian just wants to use Cucunda Li Ni
我觉得裴贤 只是想利用Cucunda李妮
as an excuse
作为借口
give an order
下达命令
To all marquises.
致所有侯爵。
Pei Xian used to be a friend of our commander.
裴贤以前是我们司令的朋友。
He cannot be underestimated.
他不能被低估。
In the absence of food supply,
在没有食物供应的情况下，
Although Pei Xian is brave and unrestrained,
裴贤虽然勇敢潇洒，
The Zhenxi Army was unable to advance at all.
镇西军根本无法前进。
Now Cui Jiajun wants to compete with us for food supplies.
现在崔家军 要和我们争夺粮食供应。
they have affected
他们已经影响了
Our great plan.
我们的好计划。
What should we do now?
我们现在应该做什么？
Oh ya, Shiqi.
Oh ya, Shiqi.
when we go,
当我们去，
Pease was taken away by Guo Zhi's people
皮斯被郭治的人带走了
and be restricted.
并被限制。
Isn't Pease a child?
皮斯不是小孩子吗？
Enter the Zhilu Parliament?
进入直鲁议会？
How about we help him?
我们帮帮他怎么样？
I'll take you to see the show tomorrow .
明天我带你去 看演出。
lieutenant,
中尉，
What should we do now?
我们现在应该做什么？
I think we can use tools
我认为我们可以使用工具
A native of Zhilu Bureau.
直禄局人。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
please sign in.
请登录。
The young master sent someone to deliver the letter.
少爷派人 把信送来了。
Any news about his great-grandson?
有他曾孙的消息吗？
so.
所以。
lieutenant if so
中尉 如果是的话
The young master will definitely mark the envelope again.
少爷一定会 在信封上再做记号的。
Send more people,
派更多的人，
We must meet his great-grandson as soon as possible.
我们必须尽快见到他的曾孙。
Don't let others seize the opportunity first.
不要让别人 先抓住这个机会。
We must meet his great-grandson immediately
我们必须立即见到他的曾孙
Only in this way can Cui Jiajun be recognized by the royal family.
只有这样，崔家军才能 得到皇室的认可。
Then,
然后，
Li Ni's granddaughter is Pei Xian's excuse
李妮的孙女就是裴贤找的借口
Will be a source of laughter.
将成为笑声的源泉。
of.
的。
When I was in Yingzhou, I said:
我在瀛州的时候 就说过：
The Li family is old and useless.
李家老了，没用了。
they have no ability
他们没有能力
And the throne will definitely be usurped.
而王位肯定会被篡夺。
The grandsons of the Li family are only good at gambling
李家的孙子们 只擅长赌博
have fun.
玩得开心。
No one can hold such a high position.
没有人能够 承担如此高的职位。
So the lieutenant submitted
于是，中尉提交了
The commander-in-chief and the young master led the army out of Yingzhou.
令帅与少主 率军出郢州。
They can compete for the throne,
他们可以争夺王位，
Why can't we fight?
为什么我们不能战斗？
If you want the world to be peaceful and the people to be peaceful,
如果你想让这个世界和平 ，人民能够和平，
Maybe this can only depend on Cui Jiajun.
或许这只能取决于 崔家军了。
Wangzhou topographic map?
望州地形图？
Are you still thinking about this?
你还在想这个吗？
If Wangzhou is captured,
若攻克望州，
The food supply problem is half solved.
粮食供应问题 就解决了一半。
(Wangzhou) Stop thinking about it and relax.
(望州) 别再想了，放松点。
I've scheduled their shifts.
我已经安排了他们的轮班。
That's it,
就是这样，
I will stay in this room at night
晚上我会住在这个房间里
In the middle of the night,
在深夜，
Bao is on duty.
宝正在值班。
It's enough.
已经足够。
Erduo, you are still injured.
二朵，你还受伤了。
Let me do the work.
让我来做这个工作吧。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
How about I sleep with you tonight?
你说 今晚我和你一起睡怎么样？
It's enough.
已经足够。
Your feet are rotten and you don’t wash them every day.
你的脚烂了 ，你又不每天洗。
if i sleep with you
如果我和你一起睡
Shall I not rot and die?
难道我不会 腐烂而死吗？
prince...
王子...
The prince is really troublesome.
太子实在是太麻烦了。
Why should you wash your feet every day?
为什么要每天洗脚？
Erduo, smell it.
二朵，你闻一闻。
Are my feet rotten?
我的脚烂了吗？
go out.
出去。
Don't think I didn't see you.
别以为我没看到你。
you again?
又是你？
Give it back to me.
把它还给我。
What?
什么？
Is this what you're referring to?
你指的是这个吗？
Where are my pearls?
我的珍珠在哪里？
Just return it first.
你先退货吧。
you are a woman
你是一个女人
But what you did was cruel.
但你的行为很残忍。
Wait a moment.
等一下。
Mr. Pei, I know the plight of his great-grandson.
裴先生，我知道他曾孙的处境。
how do you know?
你怎么知道？
Is your surname Cui?
你姓崔吗？
Why should I tell you?
我为什么要告诉你？
Where is she?
她在哪？
Why did you just wash your feet and not come back?
为什么你只洗了脚就不回来了？
Shiqi!
Shiqi!
Baby, here I come!
宝，我来了！
Lady Li Ni! Why did you fall into the well?
李妮大人！ 你为什么掉进井里？
I'll take you upstairs now .
我现在带你 上楼。
Wait a moment.
等一下。
Shiqi, are you okay?
诗琪你还好吗？
You just want to wash your feet
你只是想洗脚
Why did you fall into the well?
你为什么掉进井里？
I wanted to save a wild cat before,
之前我想救 一只野猫，
But he scratched me
但他抓伤了我
I fell in.
我掉进去了。
This animal is wild and difficult to tame
这种动物很野生，很难驯服
and unconsciously,
并且无意识地，
Why do you want to save him?
你为什么要救他？
of,
的，
In fact, he is wild and difficult to tame.
事实上，他很狂野，很难驯服。
He also has many tricks up his sleeve.
他还有很多招数。
Many skills?
技巧多多？
I want to change clothes.
我想换衣服。
OK
好的。
Joy!
悦！
Look what I got you!
看看我给你带来了什么！
Yue, this is Kodai Makande buns.
悦，这是科代马坎德化的包子。
The weather is still very hot.
天气还很热。
I was lining up to buy it.
我当时正在排队买。
Thanks.
谢谢。
There is also a golden osmanthus tea
还有一种黄金桂茶叶
Paired with fruits,
与水果搭配，
Coincidentally, we can make fruit tea.
巧合的是我们可以泡水 果茶。
fruit tea?
水果茶？
Joy,
悦，
You must not know
你一定不知道
I'm not happy I came out
我不高兴我出来了
Give this to you.
把这个给你。
If it weren't for my bribery
如果不是因为 我行贿
Commander Guo,
郭司令，
I absolutely cannot...
我绝对不能...
Did you have breakfast
你吃早餐了吗
Joy,
悦，
you asked me before
你之前问过我
What if I had breakfast?
如果我吃过早餐呢？
Joy,
悦，
Do you care about me
你在乎我吗
How about we have breakfast together ?
我们一起吃早餐怎么样 ？
Just in time we can make fruit tea.
正好 我们可以煮水果茶。
OK
好的。
(Dewan Zhilu)
(Dewan Zhilu)
What are you doing? You can't enter!
你在干什么？ 你不能进入！
Go to the side!
去旁边！
Where is Mr. Si?
斯先生在哪里？
Where did you hide him?
你把他藏到哪里去了？
Take him out!
带他出去！
quickly!
快速地！
Everyone says that the third lady of the Qu family
人人都说 曲家三小姐
I play the pipa very well.
琵琶弹得很好。
I heard,
我听说，
But he can't compare to you.
但他根本无法与你相比。
Look at your slender hands...
看看你那双纤细的手……
Damn it!
该死！
There was a group of people there who looked violent.
那里有一群人 ，看上去很暴力。
They said Mrs. Pi sent them here
他们说是皮太太派他们来的
Go find Pease.
去找皮斯。
this...
这...
that woman
那个女人
Did you send someone here too?
你也派人过来了吗？
Wait a moment.
等一下。
If you come out like this, others will find out.
你这样出来， 别人发现就好了。
Why don't you change your clothes?
你为什么不换衣服？
And dress up with a new look?
并以新的面貌打扮？
Who are you?
你是谁？
Who asked you to hug me?
谁叫你抱我的？
Is it that woman?
是那个女人吗
Who sent you here?
谁派你来这里的？
Let me go!
让我走！
What are you looking at?
你在看什么？
Look again, the lady will go to the station to report
你再看， 小姐就去车站报到
Check the road council later.
稍后再搜知路议会。
I divorced him when I came back.
回来后我就和他离婚。
Let me go!
让我走！
Useless girl!
没用的丫头！
Do you want to die?
你想死吗？
Who sent you?
谁派你来的？
Let me go!
让我走！
Come in!
进来！
Pi Si!
Pi Si!
The lady said you lied to her.
那位女士说你骗了她。
You said you were out
你说你出去了
Sell ​​food to the army to eliminate the rebels.
向军队出售粮食以消灭叛乱分子。
Actually, you went to Zhiludang
其实你去了知禄堂
Listen to a song.
听一首歌。
The lady told me to break your teeth first
女士告诉我先把你的牙齿打碎
As soon as I see you
我一看到你
build!
盖！
No...
不...
Please let me go.
请放我走。
I really didn't cheat on him.
我真的没有欺骗他。
I didn't lie to him.
我没有骗他。
Believe me.
相信我。
In fact, you also said
其实你也说了
He can give me a chance to explain
他可以给 一个解释的机会
for you.
给你。
so...
所以...
I've been slandered.
我被诽谤了。
I actually sell grain to Commander Guo.
我其实是 给郭司令卖粮食的。
I didn't cheat on my wife.
我没有欺骗我的妻子。
I know the way
我则知路会
On the way back,
回去的路上，
So I went in.
所以我进去了。
nonsense.
废话。
open mouth!
张开嘴！
This is indeed true.
这确实是事实。
I...I have a medal.
我……我有一枚奖章。
Commander Guo handed it over
郭司令交给了
Medals distributed food to me.
奖牌给我分发食物。
I dare not cheat on my wife.
我不敢欺骗我的妻子。
I actually went to sell food.
我其实是去 卖粮食的。
Where are the medals?
奖牌在哪里？
In the bag on the waist.
腰间的包里。
No.
不。
It's impossible.
是不可能的。
Indeed it is in the bag.
确实它在袋子里。
-nonsense. -no...
-废话。 -不是...
-This is impossible. - You don't even have a medal!
-这不可能。 - 你连奖牌都没有！
I did not lie to you.
我没有骗你。
Do you want to deceive us?
你想欺骗我们吗？
I actually have a medal.
我真的有一枚奖牌。
-Tear his mouth off! -I did not lie to you.
-把他的嘴撕下来！ -我没有骗你。
I really do!
我真的有！
I don't know where he went
我不知道他去了哪里
This medal.
这枚奖牌。
Tell your lady the job was well done.
告诉你的小姐， 任务完成得很好。
This is what we promise you.
这就是我们向您承诺的。
This is your redemption letter.
这是您的赎回信。
(Redemption Letter)
（赎回信）
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
Pi Si
Pi Si
It didn't look like he was lying.
看起来他不像在说谎。
I don't think he knew how the medal disappeared.
我想他不知道 奖牌是怎么消失的。
Obviously, the Cui family is faster
显然，崔家的速度更快
And get it first.
并先得到它。
remember this plan
记住这个计划
Can cheat and know where the medals are,
可以作弊并知道 奖牌的位置，
I do not think so
我不这么认为
We just help others.
我们只是帮助别人。
But that's okay.
不过，没关系。
Pi Si
Pi Si
We have
我们有
We also know where the delivery team is.
我们也知道 送餐团队的位置。
If we take him to chase the team
如果我们带他 去追球队
We may well be able to seize food supplies.
我们很可能能够 夺取粮食供应。
There are thousands of Western troops nearby ,
附近有数千镇西军 ，
They can help us.
他们可以帮助我们。
Time is running out.
没时间了。
What?
什么？
If I were from the Cui family
如果我是崔家的人
Now I will take people
现在我会带人
Disguised as soldiers guarding Wangzhou
伪装 成镇守望州的士兵
And go outside the city to receive food supplies
并前往城外 领取食物补给
Carrying medals openly.
公然携带奖牌。
According to Commander Guo’s order,
按照郭司令的命令，
We went out of town to get food.
我们出城 去领取食物。
Cows have milk, and cows have names.
牛有牛奶，牛有名字。
We still missed the opportunity.
我们仍然错过了机会。
What should we do now?
我们现在应该做什么？
Can't let Cui Jiajun
不能让崔家军
use this opportunity.
借此机会。
Of course this is a bad thing.
当然这是一件坏事。
After Sun Jing's rebellion,
孙敬叛乱后，
Cui Jiajun
崔家军
I'm used to taking advantage.
我习惯了利用。
this time,
这次，
It should be our turn.
应该轮到我们了。
it's useless!
没用的！
I told you to watch out for food vendors
我告诉过你要注意 食品供应商
(Guo's residence) But he can also disappear.
（郭的住所） 但他也可以消失。
I really don't think so
我真的不这么认为
Peace will be kidnapped
皮斯会被绑架
The same goes for daytime.
白天也是如此。
I've killed the guilty colonel.
我已经杀死了 有罪的上校。
Commander, please punish me according to military law.
指挥官，请 按照军法处罚我。
(Wangzhou official) I don’t have time
(望州官) 我没时间
(Guo Zhi, Sun Jing’s subordinate) I’ll kill you now.
（孙敬部下郭治） 现在斩你。
Order the troops to go outside the city to collect food supplies.
命令军队到城外 领取粮食补给。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
how?
如何？
Even if we deliberately take the longer route
即使我们刻意 走更长的路
To avoid collision with Guo Zhi,
以免与郭志相撞，
we only exist
我们只存在
There were 300 people nearby.
附近有300人。
Now we have 100 people going out with us to get food.
现在有 100 个人和我们一起出去 领取食物。
Only 200 people entered Wangzhou. Is this enough?
进入望州才两百人， 这够了吗？
If Guo Zhi knew that military supplies were confiscated,
如果郭治知道 军需品被没收的话，
He will definitely feel anxious
他肯定会感到焦虑
And led the army out of the city to collect food and grass.
并率军出城 领取粮草。
Therefore, the defense in the city is no longer tight.
所以，城内的防守不再严密。
We have 200 people
我们有200人
Just take the opportunity to break into this city
只需要趁机 闯入这座城市
and kill defenders by surprise .
并出其不意地杀死防守者 。
When we returned to the city again,
当我们再次回到市区后，
We continue to close the city’s doors.
我们继续关闭城市的大门。
In fact, the young master's army is coming.
事实上，少爷的军队即将到来。
we will definitely win
我们一定会赢
In this bet.
在这个赌注中。
(Wangzhou)
(Wangzhou)
Major General Pei.
裴少将。
Thousands of our troops are nearby
数千名我们的士兵 就在附近
Heading towards the city gate.
正朝着城门走去。
Bring a friend and take advantage of them.
带上朋友 来利用他们。
Report to the commander,
向指挥官报告，
An army patrol arrived two hours ago .
两个小时前， 一支军队巡逻队来了。
After matching the medals,
匹配完奖牌后，
We distributed military supplies.
我们分发军事物资。
I checked,
我检查过，
The medal is genuine
勋章是真品
And leave the food delivery team to them.
并将 送餐队伍留给他们。
How disgusting.
真恶心。
Chase them!
追他们！
(Kota Wangzhou)
(Kota Wangzhou)
(Wangzhou)
(Wangzhou)
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
Is it Cui Jiajun?
是崔家军吗
Will you seek our help?
会寻求我们的帮助吗？
They were hunted by the military,
他们遭到军方的追捕，
So they must comply with all our requirements.
所以他们必须遵守 我们的所有要求。
after,
之后，
I'd make him jump into the well
我会让他跳进井里
And soak in water first.
并先用水浸泡。
Jump into a well?
跳进井里？
Why jump into a well?
为什么要跳井呢？
Lieutenant, what should we do?
中尉，我们该怎么办？
Maybe Guo Zhi will lead an army and chase them all the way here.
说不定郭智会率领大军 ，一路追到这里。
We have food supplies.
我们有食物供应。
Tentera Zhenxi
Tentera Zhenxi
Don't want us to be caught by the enemy.
不愿意让我们被敌人抓住。
Now,
现在，
He is waiting for us to plead with them.
他正在等待我们向 他们恳求。
Then they will make their request
然后，他们会提出 他们的要求
Then consult us.
然后咨询我们。
Lieutenant, you must make a decision now.
中尉， 你现在必须做出决定。
Otherwise Guo Zhi would chase him all the way here.
不然郭治 会一路追到这里。
Lieutenant, the troops are coming.
中尉，军队来了。
Cui Jiajun is here!
崔家军来了！
Master Cui.
崔少爷。
Master Cui is here to pick us up.
崔少爷来 接我们了。
hurry up.
快点。
♪If you forget the twinkling light♪
♪如果你忘记了闪烁的光芒♪
♪Tungu Kennangan♪
♪东古肯南甘♪
♪Broken and sunk♪
♪破碎沉没♪
♪The spots that remain in my heart♪
♪留在心中的斑点♪
♪Penarikan Itu♪
♪佩纳里坎伊图♪
♪I object♪
♪我反对♪
♪If you long not to be forgotten♪
♪如果渴望不被遗忘的话♪
♪Longing to go back to the original time♪
♪渴望回到 最初的时光♪
♪The warmth that fate once had ♪
♪命运曾经拥有的温暖 ♪
♪I want to keep it for you♪
♪我想为你保留它♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪We made a promise♪
♪我们曾经约定♪
♪Even though love makes me hurt♪
♪尽管爱让我受伤♪
♪I must live for you too♪
♪我也必须为你而活♪
♪Follow the faces in your memory♪
♪追随记忆中的面孔♪
♪Waiting is my obsession♪
♪等待是我的痴迷♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪Promise to you♪
♪对你的承诺♪
♪Terbalikkan Karma♪
♪Terbalikkan 因果报应♪
♪I love you without regrets♪
♪爱你无怨无悔♪
♪I'm willing to leave it to you♪
♪我愿意把它留给你♪
♪I've been waiting for you to answer me♪
♪我一直在等你 回答我♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪Promise to you♪
♪对你的承诺♪
♪Terbalikkan Karma♪
♪Terbalikkan 因果报应♪
♪I love you without regrets♪
♪爱你无怨无悔♪
♪I'm willing to leave it to you♪
♪我愿意把它留给你♪
♪I've been waiting for you to answer me♪
♪我一直在等你 回答我♪